SAMUEL BURKETT

Conway, AR 72034 • (501) 269-3387 • sburk377@gmail.com www.samburkett.me

Professional Summary

Experienced mainframe systems programmer and full stack developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Java, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Angular, and MongoDB. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor of Science focused in Computer Science from the University of Central Arkansas.

Skills

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Computer hardware/software
- Object-Oriented Programming
- Unix/Linux
- Java
- JavaScript

- Visual Studio
- REST APIs
- Django
- Python
- IBM zEnterprise
- SMPE
- Mainframe Software

Education

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science, 2017 **University of Central Arkansas** - Conway, AR

Work History

Mainframe Systems Programmer, 05/2017 to Current

Ensono – Conway, AR

- Use ISPF/TSO for editing and production work
- Install OEM and third party software on z/OS systems
- Use CA ServiceDesk and ServiceNow to create change orders and manage tickets
- Upgrade and implement new software versions and maintenance levels to test and production systems using SMP/E
- Provide technical support and guidance to clients
- Develop and maintain batch/online systems.

- Mentor new associates on installing software on the mainframe and how to adhere to company and client standards
- Analyze the job log and resolve production ABENDs; perform impact analysis to resolve user queries.
- Provide 24x7 on-call support to resolve technical issues, specifically storage related
- Actively collaborate with the team to discuss technical or design ideas during project development process.
- Support end users to provide the preparation and scheduling of program modifications and user requested enhancements.
- Supported the DB2 subsystems during DR testing
- Replicated production DB2 subsystems onto test systems

Intern Desktop Support Technician, 08/2016 to 01/2017

Acxiom Corporation – Conway, AR

- Managed inventory
- Utilized assets for redistribution
- Handled inter-department shipping between locations
- Installed and maintained user hardware phones, headsets, peripherals, monitors, cable management
- Imaged and deployed company computers with designated company requirements
- Provided technical support to associates while transitioning between locations during remodels

Intern Data Entry/Desktop Support, 01/2011 to 12/2013

Liberty Opportunities – Conway, AR

- Removed and replaced malfunctioning components to correct hardware problems.
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Created and configured client database
- Managed and supported client database
- Contacted vendors regarding purchase orders and shipping queries
- Assisted clients with questions and concerns over phone or email